# I AN HI LDEBRAND

ian@hildy.io | (512) 850-4265 Austin, TX 78735

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am an accomplished Chief Technology Officer and Web Developer with expertise in strategic planning, project leadership, and driving business growth. I have a track record of processing \$700k in payments and serving 30,000 customers. In my current role as CTO at Nexus Finance, I develop long-term strategic plans, manage company-level architecture, and coordinate with vendors and client IT teams. As CEO and Web Developer at Linear, I've generated over \$5 million for clients and increased company revenue by 300% in one month through marketing strategies. I have a strong background in web design and development and am currently working on my Bachelor's degree in Business Administration with a minor in Innovation & Entrepreneurship from The University of Texas At Dallas.

#### **EDUCATION**

The University of Texas At Dallas - Richardson, TX BBA: Innovation & Entrepreneurship

#### WORK HISTORY

Chief Technology Officer | Nexus Finance - Remote, Company Is Utah Based

- Developed and implemented long-term strategic technological blueprint.

  06/2023 Current
- Provided project leadership in dynamic technology-driven environment with multiple priorities.
- Facilitated ongoing team development and growth through training and professional skills enhancement.
- Laid out complete business continuity plan to maintain data protection in event of natural disaster or long-term outage.
- Managed company-level architecture, platform and data configuration processes and implementation protocols.
- Coordinated third-party vendors and client IT teams to seamlessly deliver effective solutions.

Website: https://trynexus.io

- Managed partnerships and strategic business relationships by negotiating contract terms and handling conflicts.
- 500+ Business Customers (Q2 2023)
- Services offered generated over \$5 million for clients.
- Increased company revenue by 300% through aggressive new marketing strategies in one month.
- Established foundational processes for business operations.

Website: https://hirelinear.com/

Design Technologist - Internship | H-E-B Digital - Austin, TX 05/2023 - 08/2023

- Spearheaded a new project to dramatically improve customer satisfaction scores using generative AI.
- Extended internship to successfully finalize an advanced prototype before transitioning project ownership to stakeholders upon commencement of college studies.
- Subject to NDA, no further details available.
- For those outside of Texas H-E-B is the 6th largest private company based in the United States by revenue (Forbes 2022)

Website: https://digital.heb.com/

CEO | Travis County Detail - Austin, TX

05/2022 - 08/2023

- Coached and guided contractors to improve job satisfaction and achieve higher performance levels.
- Established foundational processes for business operations.
- Engaged positively with staff and leadership colleagues, soliciting and encouraging feedback and collaborative spirit.
- Increased company revenue over \$10,000 through aggressive new market strategies.

Website: https://tcdetail.net

Software Developer - Internship | H-E-B Digital - Austin, TX 05/2022 - 07/2022

- Designing, developing, and integrating solutions in ARC GIS software based on business requirements and objectives.
- Performing internal system acceptance to deliver well-tested enhancements and meet business requirements.
- Analyzing existing systems and databases and recommending enhancements to solve business needs in multiple departments of HEB.
- For those outside of Texas H-E-B is the 6th largest private company based in the United States by revenue (Forbes 2022)

Website: https://digital.heb.com/

- Collaborated with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Worked cooperatively with client services, sales and design team in deadlinedriven environment.
- Made recommendations for new technology integration based on suitability and alignment to business goals.
- Coordinated with digital content manager to obtain content for updates and expansions.
- Advocated for well-tested and documented, high quality code.
- Guided customers on project stages and iterations with input on best practices, user needs and technology capabilities.

Website: https://ensora.co/

# CERTIFICATIONS

- Web Developer Bootcamp Colt Steele
- Microsoft Office 2016 (Word, Excel, PWPT)

# SKILLS

- Sales expertise
- Complaint resolution
- Business Management
- Creative problem solving
- Project budget estimations
- Contract Management

- Web Design & Development
- UX Design
- HTML, CSS, React.js, Node.js, GitHub & Git
- Website optimization
- Figma Designing Software

# WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

https://hildy.io

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ian-hildebrand/

• https://github.com/ihildy

## HOBBIES

Podcasts (WVFRM and WAN Show are in my rotation)
Cars (Races at Circuit of the Americas and Porsche Club of America)